TYLERCHONG9641@GMAIL.COM

TYLER CHONG

SUMMARY

Tyler is a skilled full-stack developer with a demonstrated history of working in the finance and insurance industries. He is proficient with modern JavaScript frameworks and libraries. He has demonstrated professional experience with the MERN and MEAN stack.

EDUCATION

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Apr 2011 - Oct 2013, Toronto

Master of Computer Science

- Software Engineering
- Cyber Security

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Apr 2005 - Oct 2009, Toronto

Bachelor of Computer Science

- Computer Science
- Software Engineering
- 00P(Object-oriented programming) languages
- Cyber Security

SKILLS

Web Programming: React, Vue, Angular, TypeScript, Javascript, Next.js, Nuxt.js, NgRx

Design: Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, InvisionApp

Mobile Programming: React Native, Xamarins, Swift

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon DynamoDB

Testing: Unit Testing, E2E Testing

Platforms: Linux, iOS, Windows, Docker

Tools: Git, IDE, Amazon Web Service

EXPERIENCE

Vieworks, Toronto - Front-End Developer

October 2020 - April 2021

Wealthsimple, Toronto - Full Stack Developer

January 2019 - September 2020

- Handled the full-stack development on the Wealthsimple for the Advisors product (Wealthsimple's B2B offering that enables financial advisors to focus on delivering value to their clients).
- Implemented white labeling: a key player to our internal design system of themeable React components, eliminating theme-related bugs.
- Implemented the associate role: this feature saves advisors time by allowing them to invite colleagues to securely manage their clients.
- Rewrote the "log in as client" functionality ("impersonation"): the feature allows advisors to perform actions on behalf of their clients the way the client would themselves.

Mitre Media, Hong Kong, Toronto - Full Stack Developer

December 2016 - December 2018

- Reduced server response time significantly using different caching strategies, assets management, and database querying optimization in MySQL.
- Architected and implemented a front-end system for React Application with Material UI and Styled Components and animation using React Pose.
- Incorporated ReactJS strategies such as higher-order components, render props, and global state management using Apollo client caching.
- Proposed and developed GraphQL endpoint for its advantage of a single source of data while developing GraphQL schema foundation in Rails and reusable Querying/Mutation structure in React.

WeAlwin Technologies, Hong Kong- Full Stack Developer

January 2014 - November 2016

- Administered a reusable in-house web app to process issues and commit data from Redmine and Jira for SR&ED review using a pure JavaScript solution.
- Promoted code quality and standards by implementing various custom Git commit hooks.
- Employed PHP mass detector and PHP linting tools to maintain code integrity and visibility among the development team.

FLYDESK, Hong Kong - Full Stack Developer

January 2010 - February 2011

- Implemented a redesigned version of the public website.
- Created multiple landing pages with reusable components.
- Created responsive emails with MJML for use in Drip campaigns.
- Analyzed data in Google Analytics and provided new insights.
- Implemented a signup gateway with the main app, with Google and Facebook social sign-in.

SOCIAL PROFILES

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-chong-203972199/

Github: https://github.com/rogue707Dev

StackOverFlow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/12756481/tyler-chong?tab=profile

Portfolio: http://tylerchong.herokuapp.com/